<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[One guy's blog about life, design, games and code.]]></description><link>https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 14:43:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Dengue fever]]></title><description><![CDATA[Life often finds a way to mess with your plans. Just when I want to blog more, I get hit with dengue fever. Worst sickness of my past 1…]]></description><link>https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/dengue-fever/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/dengue-fever/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Life often finds a way to mess with your plans. Just when I want to blog more, I get hit with dengue fever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worst sickness of my past 10 years at least. High fever, a headache so bad I don’t even want to look at any screen for days, lethargy, widespread itchy rash. It’s a nasty melange of symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s over now. I have a draft in progress for literotica. Hope I can finish it this week 😀.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Getting back to blogging]]></title><description><![CDATA[I’m back to the blog, after a long break. I wrote a bunch of draft posts but they ended up too ambitious and now they’ve rotten through the…]]></description><link>https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/on-getting-back-to-blogging/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/on-getting-back-to-blogging/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’m back to the blog, after a long break. I wrote a bunch of draft posts but they ended up too ambitious and now they’ve rotten through the passage of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now I’m back and I hope to write more. Writing is creating and I’m a creator 🙂.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[On the merits and problems of gacha games]]></title><description><![CDATA[Genshin Impact I’ve been enjoying Genshin Impact for about a year or more now. It is truly an excellent game. The game has a deep, smooth…]]></description><link>https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/on-the-merits-and-problems-of-gacha-games/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/on-the-merits-and-problems-of-gacha-games/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h4&gt;Genshin Impact&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been enjoying &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c7E_WQfX4Fs&amp;#x26;ab_channel=ONGame&quot;&gt;Genshin Impact&lt;/a&gt; for about a year or more now. It is truly an excellent game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game has a deep, smooth, innovative combat system, great UIUX, gorgeous graphics, vast content, rich lore, incredible music, amazing characters, breathtaking landscapes and touching stories. However, many gamers simply won’t even give it a chance because of its divisive gacha system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Brief description of Genshin’s gacha system&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Players use ingame currency which they can earn by playing the game or purchase by spending money to (mainly) acquire new characters to bring into their party and play as. However, there is a luck/gambling element to this, as the process involves chance. If a player is unlucky, they could spend up to 75% more ingame currency than a player with average luck to acquire one character. &lt;em&gt;Math based on 61.5 average pulls for a 5 star with 50% chance of hitting the 50/50 versus 160 pulls for soft pity missing the 50/50.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the rate that a player can earn ingame currency through playing the game and spending no money, a player can acquire about 1/3 to 1/2 of the rare-tier characters in the game. There are also common-tier characters, which are easily available even to players spending no money (free to play, or f2p, players).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Good gacha and bad gacha&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think that gacha is inherently good or bad. It’s simply a method of monetization in gaming (which has been a problem for the gaming industry since forever). But I think gacha does have a bad reputation because it’s often employed in games which have other negative qualities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Pay-to-win, pay-for-variety, pay-for-cosmetics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, many gacha games have some sort of PvP (player versus player) mode. The players who spend money purchasing ingame currency bully the f2p players, pushing out f2p players, shrinking the bulk of the player base while driving a spending arms race. The issue here is the pay-to-win system, where you can’t compete unless you pay money. That’s toxic. Genshin, by design, has no PvP mode. They don’t even have a competitive leaderboard for challenging content, so there’s no ingame support for competition whatsoever. You can complete the most challenging content in the game (and earn the ingame currency for it) without spending a cent, and some hardcore ascetics have even done so without even spending any free ingame currency from playing the game. That’s why I’d say that Genshin is pay-for-variety, which is &lt;strong&gt;not evil&lt;/strong&gt;. The other successful, not evil monetization system is pay-for-cosmetics, employed successfully by giants like DotA 2 and Fortnite. Players are not forced to spend money to compete in and enjoy the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Limited gameplay in many gacha games&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another common negative trait of gacha games is their limited gameplay, with a focus of the game being on collecting the gacha items/characters themselves. An example of this is in auto-battlers, like Raid Shadow Legends, where almost all of the actual gameplay plays out automatically. But this doesn’t have to be the case. The gameplay in Genshin is top-of-the-line AAA quality, and combat is done in Action RPG style, where skill and knowledge are much more important factors than character statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Promotion of locked content in gacha&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think there are four, essential parts which make up gacha. One is content locked behind ingame currency, two is the advertising/promotion of such content, three is chance and four is a high limit on spending. I haven’t talked about the advertising part yet, so I’ll say a little. All gacha games have some kind of promotional media for the locked content. The most common are ingame “banners” which show where players go to chance for the desired assets and video demos of the characters/items. Better games (like Genshin) don’t overtly present these advertisements to the player at every opportunity, whereas many games will brandish such promotional material to players on every login, at checkpoints and also just periodically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Chance, the essence of gacha&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third piece of the gacha system is chance. Chance can induce happiness chemicals and behavioral reinforcement through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.verywellmind.com/what-is-a-variable-ratio-schedule-2796012&quot;&gt;variable payout schedules&lt;/a&gt;. Chance can also cause players to spend more than they initially planned due to sunk cost fallacy. It is the extra spice that boosts sales for games, that casinos and lotteries have been using forever. But I don’t think it’s evil in itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Gaming whales and their importance in the player base ecosystem&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth ingredient to gacha is a high effective limit on spending. Even though a player can spend ingame currency (or real money) to acquire a character, they can also pay up to 15 times that base amount, in order to power up that character. Most players don’t do this, but many, called whales in the vernacular, do. It could be a way to show their special attachment to that character, or they could just have too much money to spend. These whales often make up a large proportion of a gacha game’s income, allowing f2p players to ride on their coat-tails and enjoy the game for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has several big benefits. For the gaming studio, this is a way to get richer customers to spend more. Compared to the traditional pay-to-own model, where you pay for the game once and play it forever, whales allow gaming studios to earn much more, and to keep earning money for continuously producing good content. Compared to the pay-for-cosmetics model, it’s easier to get thousands of dollars from a player since skins usually are not so individually expensive. The whales also pay for the costs of maintaining f2p players, allowing the game to have an organically large player base and to spread through word of mouth and through gaming friends and communities. For players, this is of course excellent for f2p players who get to enjoy a great game at absolutely no cost, allowing the game to be enjoyed by millions in poorer regions of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The morality of gacha and casinos&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is gacha evil by cheating players of money by subjecting them to hard-sell sweaty salesperson tactics? I don’t think so, not any more than a salesperson is evil for selling any item that salesperson doesn’t think is the very best for the customer. If salespeople only sold what they thought was in the best interest of prospective customers, we would hardly have any salespeople in the world. The bulk of the burden and responsibility must lie with the consumer and their discernment. In the same way, players must be responsible for what they purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is gacha evil by cheating the uninformed who do not understand probabilities? I don’t think so either. A fool and his money are soon parted anyway. In this respect, gacha is surely less evil than the gambling industry, because fools can lose their life savings in a gambling den trying to win back their losses, but even an imbecile knows that they can’t get back any money that they put into a gacha game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The upside of gacha&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think gacha is here to stay, and I’m all for it. It’s a successful monetization method for games, and allows great game development studios like Genshin’s Hoyoverse to continue to produce stellar content. Let’s just hope that players are discerning enough to protect their wallets from bad gacha games and bad purchases.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[I Wrote the Jigoku Game Log Chrome Extension]]></title><description><![CDATA[I recently wrote my first chrome extension, Jigoku Game Log. Jigoku Jigoku is an excellent online implementation of the excellent card game…]]></description><link>https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/jigoku-chrome-extension/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/jigoku-chrome-extension/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I recently wrote my first chrome extension, &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/jigoku-game-log/cofpncfeggiibpickflljahgmhabgkeg&quot;&gt;Jigoku Game Log&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Jigoku&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jigoku is an excellent online implementation of the excellent card game &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fantasyflightgames.com/en/products/legend-of-the-five-rings-the-card-game/&quot;&gt;Legend of the Five Rings&lt;/a&gt;. Game events are logged as messages in a chat area in a corner of the page, together with any chat between the players. No game replays are saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Jigoku Game Log&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jigoku Game Log goes into the DOM to extract the game events, omits superfluous information like chat messages, summarises and formats important information, and then sends this newly-produced game log to &lt;a href=&quot;https://markdownshare.com&quot;&gt;markdownshare.com&lt;/a&gt; to be saved for sharing and saving, for either analysis or sharing war stories with comrades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Challenges&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;const&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;let&lt;/code&gt; gave me errors, so I used &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;var&lt;/code&gt; throughout. I guess this might be because the script is constantly ongoing and doesn’t get garbage collected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Submitting the game log to markdownshare.com through the fetch API was difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, Chrome doesn’t allow fetch API from most areas in the extension. It needs to be done in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;background.js&lt;/code&gt;, so &lt;strong&gt;message passing&lt;/strong&gt; needs to be used to get the fetch request to &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;background.js&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, I had issues with permissions, with my request not getting sent, with no informative error logs. Turns out, there are several places to add the cross-origin site permissions to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, the API usage example on markdownshare.com showed the use of cURL. What I didn’t realise, what that cURL automatically sends the message with &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;ContentType:application/x-www-form-urlencoded&lt;/code&gt; when using the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;-d&lt;/code&gt; option, so I needed to specify this manually with &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;fetch&lt;/code&gt; and I also needed to do &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;encodeURIComponent()&lt;/code&gt; on the text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 10 users in the L5R community are using the extension 😊.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Writing VSCode Extensions]]></title><description><![CDATA[After writing my first chrome extension last week. Today, I explored writing a language support vscode extension for writing TagUI scripts…]]></description><link>https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/writing-vscode-extensions/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/writing-vscode-extensions/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;After writing my first chrome extension last week. Today, I explored writing a language support vscode extension for writing TagUI scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Interesting capabilities of vscode extensions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access the filesystem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Register commands to the command palette.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Register context menu items (when right-clicking).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Store data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Display notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get user input through a wizard (called QuickPick).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change colors of code/UI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change file icons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show info when hovering some api.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add autocomplete for a language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show information in the status bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show custom content (with WebView API).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlight syntax for a language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;On language extensions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can write a &lt;strong&gt;Language Server&lt;/strong&gt;, which is text-editor-agnostic, or just code directly for vscode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll write more as I discover more.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Working on Material UI usage page]]></title><description><![CDATA[I’m currently working on a teaching page for the usage of Material UI, since I found the concept pretty tough to grok from the docs and I…]]></description><link>https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/material-ui-usage-wip/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/material-ui-usage-wip/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’m currently working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://siowyisheng.github.io/mui-usage/&quot;&gt;a teaching page&lt;/a&gt; for the usage of Material UI, since I found the concept pretty tough to grok from the docs and I couldn’t find good resources elsewhere, especially for Material UI v4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m mostly done with the navigation and structure of the site. I’ll just clean up article pages and add a ScrollToTopOnMount and complete the content. ☺️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: This is currently discontinued.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[On emojis]]></title><description><![CDATA[Emojis are excellent. They are vectorised and thus scalable without loss of quality. They are colorful. They are well-drawn and well…]]></description><link>https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/on-emojis/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/on-emojis/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Emojis are excellent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are vectorised and thus scalable without loss of quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are colorful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are well-drawn and well-designed (and have to be).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are numerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They allow usage of images in APIs which ordinarily only work with text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are awesome!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[On designing]]></title><description><![CDATA[Emulate before innovate. Don’t reinvent the wheel. Be willing to kill your babies. Create quickly. Destroy mercilessly.]]></description><link>https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/on-designing/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/on-designing/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Emulate before innovate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t reinvent the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be willing to kill your babies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create quickly. Destroy mercilessly.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[On free will]]></title><description><![CDATA[If I want to move my hand, I can just decide to move it. Nothing stops me from doing so. *moves hand* See? But the question is, did I move…]]></description><link>https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/on-free-will/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://siowyisheng.github.io/blog/on-free-will/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;If I want to move my hand, I can just decide to move it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing stops me from doing so. *&lt;em&gt;moves hand&lt;/em&gt;* See?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the question is, did I move my hand because I chose and decided to? Can my conscious thought &lt;strong&gt;drive&lt;/strong&gt; this action?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Defining the question&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start at the top. What &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; consciousness? The first definition offered by a google search is “a state of being aware of and responsive to one’s surroundings”. Two ideas are being offered here: &lt;em&gt;perception&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;responsiveness&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitting here in my chair, I can hear a car driving past. The sound waves reach my ear drums and my brain registers the signal. It enters my short-term memory and I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; it happens. I &lt;em&gt;perceive&lt;/em&gt; it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But more than this. I perceive my own thoughts. I perceive myself weighing different options. I perceive my emotions, my sensations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My leg starts to get uncomfortable from being in the same position for too long. I sense the discomfort, feel that I should move it, and my brain sends the signal to my leg muscles to adjust its position. I &lt;em&gt;respond&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting that these two ideas are tied together in the definition, as if they are somehow &lt;em&gt;related&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how about consciousness being a state? Is it a physical state? A mental state? What even &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a mental state? It can’t be a state of consciousness, of awareness and perception, or that would be a circular definition. Probably, what we mean by a mental state is a &lt;em&gt;physical representation&lt;/em&gt; of one’s nervous system and the chemicals, hormones and charged/discharged states of neurons in all the different sections of one’s brain. This sounds strange, but is intuitive in some way: everything else has a physical representation in the world, so why should consciousness(and by extension, conscious thought) be any different?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it all together, consciousness is the physical state of perceiving and responding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Explaining the apparent conscious direction of thought&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about conscious thought? It appears, that I am able to direct my attention, my awareness towards different directions. I can think about my fingers pressing the keys, about my breath, or the itch on my cheek. Our earlier definition of consciousness already has an answer for this. The physical system of my nervous system and brain interact, together with the input sensory data through my eyes, ears, nerves, in deterministic physical processes to go from one “mental state” to the next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, there was no other way I could have responded in that situation. I couldn’t have &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; moved my hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How could that be? &lt;em&gt;I thought about my hand, and decided to move it, and moved it. I’ve been doing this my whole life!&lt;/em&gt; Well, correlation does not imply causation. The perception of thinking about my hand, of deciding to move it, and of subsequently of it moving, does not mean that my awareness caused my hand to move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For how could it? How can the immaterial affect the material? My perception is merely that, perception. The physical processes of my body are managed by the state of my neurons, my hormones. &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt;(or the perception of &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt;) am nothing but a passenger with a toy steering wheel in this car that is my mind. &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; am a projection on the monitor that merely reflects what is happening within the CPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more realistic picture of how my hand moved follows. My brain is wired to seek certain outcomes(exactly &lt;em&gt;which&lt;/em&gt; outcomes is a topic for another treatise). One of those outcomes is to prove points. I was trying to make a point about conscious thought, and so my system moved my hand to prove the point, with the side-effect of my perception thinking that it was the one who did the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Introducing terms for clarity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here on out, I will refer to our conscious mind and awareness, the passenger in the car as our &lt;strong&gt;consciousness&lt;/strong&gt;, and the physical systems of our brains and nervous system, together with our sensory input, which actually cause our actions as our &lt;strong&gt;mental state&lt;/strong&gt;. The consciousness is born from the mental state, as a side effect of perception for sensory input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The consequences of determinism&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our consciousness has no agency in its experiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our actions are purely a result of our mental state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The joy or tragedy of having no agency&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our mental states cause the actions which make our consciousness feel good. On the other hand, they also cause our oft humanly poor behavior, but our consciousness is the one which perceives all the suffering for it. For example, Tom’s mental state might cause him to punch his boss and get fired, but his consciousness will perceive the sadness of losing his job, the guilt and the possible subsequent drop in quality of life from lost income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Punishment and reward&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why should we punish someone if &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; never committed the crime? We should not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any kind of punishment, however, will always incidentally wrongly punish the blameless consciousness, for it is born from the mental state, whose future behavior we are trying to manipulate through the punishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The paradox of a deterministic future&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paradox is that our thoughts have agency, our perception of our thoughts has no agency, but we cannot separate the two, as one is born from the other. So where do we go from here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, the good news is that by reading and thinking about this, your mental state has &lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; begun to change. It is learning that &lt;em&gt;it&lt;/em&gt; is the cause of your sufferings and your joys, and that it has to step up its game, because your consciousness can’t do anything to help it. It is learning not to blame your consciousness for failures, not to praise your consciousness for successes, and to let your consciousness just &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt;, unbiasedly, un-afraidly, humbly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, if I want to move my hand, my mental state can just decide to move it.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>